CHAN Ka Lung, Oscar 陳嘉隆 Frontend Developer

oscarchankalung.github.io github.com/oscarchankalung ninkedin.com/in/oscarchankalung in

oscarchankalung@gmail.com ☑

A self-driven programmer embarking on a career in web development. Experienced in building the frontend of commercial web and mobile apps. Always striving to balance time, product quality and maintainability. I am motivated to position myself within an environment that has an established set of values that they adhere to, and be continually challenged both personally and technically.

Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript
- React, Angular, Redux, Sass, Bootstrap, jQuery
- Python, SQL, Git, Command Line
- Adobe Photoshop, XD, Figma

Work Experience

Frontend Developer, AppicIDEA IT Solutions

04/2021 - Present

Technologies: Typescript, React Native, Angular, Firebase, Figma, Bitbucket

- Developed the frontend of 3 React Native mobile apps on wine inventory management, online shopping and mental health promotion
- Developed the frontend of 1 Angular progressive web app on elderly service
- Adopt agile development using Atlassian technology

Technical Business Analyst, Macquarie, Hong Kong

10/2018 - 03/2020

Technologies: Alteryx, API, Confluence, MongoDB

- Incorporated new data processing tools to enable automation within the middle office
- Automated over 30 reconciliations/reports, annually saving 40 hours per workflow
- Migrated over 20 trade/position reconciliations from a vendor to the internal system, which improved the user experience and avoided the cost of a premium upgrade
- Developed an email-based daily reconciliations break monitoring tool, which made error discovery and solving faster
- Created user guides and trained eight trade supports to use Alteryx, who initiated over 20 automation

Community Manager, Coderbunker, Shanghai

12/2017 - 06/2018

Technologies: G Suite (Google Workspace), WeChat Official Account, Strikingly

- Built an international community for software developers to further develop their skills and create opportunities for collaboration with customers
- Delivered presentations and recruited people as freelancers, co-workers or co-learners
- Organized and facilitated co-learning workshops and tech events for 30-100 participants
- · Managed the official website and social media accounts for community branding
- · Maintained and improved databases using Google Spreadsheet and SQL

Education

Self-Taught Frontend Development, Online

05/2020 - Present

Technologies: React, Angular, JavaScript, Less, lint

- Learning frontend development on freeCodeCamp, MDN and Udemy
- Created a personal website hosted using GitHub Page
- Certified in responsive web design, JavaScript algorithms and data structure, and frontend libraries
- Studying Angular The Complete Guide (2021 Edition)

Java Development Training Programme, FDM Hong Kong Academy

08/2018 - 10/2018

Trained in the following modules:

- · Object Oriented Development (Java)
- Database Access in Java (JDBC, JPA/Hibernate)
- · Web Development in Java (Servlet, JSPs)
- Spring Framework

Computer Software Engineering, Piscine Program, 42 Silicon Valley, Fremont, California 06/2018 - 07/2018

Survived the admission process of the 42 program, an innovative programming school with a peer-to-peer and project-based learning environment. Zero tuition. Zero teachers. Zero classes.

- Completed an intensive 28 day coding challenge covering the basic of C, Linux, and Git
- Worked in teams to write programs, like sudoku solver and expression evaluator

BSc., Applied Biology (First Class Hons, GPA 3.54), City University of Hong Kong 09/2013 - 07/2017

Awards

FDM Consultant of the Month Award, APAC Winner, 2019

Interests and Activities

- Reading
- · Cooking
- Mindfulness
- Feminism
- Decentralized Technologies